Finding aid to the K. Frances Scott papers CA.MS.01149
Smith College Archives
K. Frances Scott papers
1924-1969
Smith College Archives
Scott, K. Frances
CA.MS.01149
0.438 linear feet (1 container)
K. Frances Scott came to Smith in 1919 as Assistant physician, a position she held until 1927 when she became Professor of Hygiene. She retired in 1955. Her papers contain legal and financial documents, news clippings, publications, research, speeches, awards, photographs, correspondence, syllabi, and biographies.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Biographical / Historical
K. Frances Scott was born in Vincennes, Indiana, to Reverend Thomas S. and Lucy Kate (Shaw) Scott in 1890. She graduated from Wooster College with a Ph.B. in 1912 and received her M.D. in 1917 from Rush Medical College. She also attended courses at Harvard School of Education, M.I.T and Teachers College at Columbia University. Scott came to Smith in 1919 as Assistant physician, a position she held until 1927 when she became Professor of Hygiene. During World War II, Scott was active at Smith and in the Northampton area as Co-chairman of Salvage for region II and Member of the Women's Division for the Massachusetts Committee of Public Safety, as First Aid Instructor for the Civilian Defense Organization, and as a Red Cross Worker. During her time at Smith, she also published many articles and pamphlets on the health of students. She served as President of the National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Trustee of the national Council for Community Improvement, member of the American Public health Association, President of the American Student Health Association, and Chairman of the Committee on Health Instruction. Scott retired in 1955. In retirement, she continued in her interests of carpentry and photography. She died in 1971.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the professional papers of K. Frances Scott, including news clippings about her career, publications, research, speeches, awards, professional photographs and correspondence, syllabi, and biographies used for obituaries. The collection also contains some personal papers, largely made up of legal and financial documents.
Scott, K. Frances
- Index, undated (Box 1014, Folder 1)
- Assistant Physician 1919-25, Associate professor of Hygiene 1927-55, 1937-1955, undated (Box 1014, Folder 2)
- Biography – Awards and Honors, 1926, undated (Box 1014, Folder 3)
- Biography – Family – Estate of Kate Shaw Scott, 1935-1936 (Box 1014, Folder 4)
- Biography – Legal and Financial Documents, 1945-1967 (Box 1014, Folder 5)
- Biography – Legal and Financial Documents, 1943-1969 (Box 1014, Folder 6)
- Biography – Legal and Financial Documents – Publications, 1938-1957 (Box 1014, Folder 7)
- Biography – News Clippings, 1948-1955 (Box 1014, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1948-1955 (Box 1014, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1014, Folder 10)
- Courses, undated (Box 1014, Folder 11)
- Publications, 1924-1948 (Box 1014, Folder 12)
- Publications – Camp Life and Physical Growth, 1931 (Box 1014, Folder 13)
- Publications – Dysmenorrhea in College, 1931 (Box 1014, Folder 14)
- Publications – Good health Habits, 1941 (Box 1014, Folder 15)
- Publications – The House Director and Student Health, undated (Box 1014, Folder 16)
- Publications – Posture Paragraphs, 1932-1933 (Box 1014, Folder 17)
- Publications – Report on the Health Knowledge Test, 1930-1931 (Box 1014, Folder 18)
- Research Notes and Material, undated (Box 1014, Folder 19)
- Research Notes and Material – Feet, 1942 (Box 1014, Folder 20)
- Speeches – Papers read before ASHA, 1932 (Box 1014, Folder 21)
- Speeches, 1926-1942 (Box 1014, Folder 22)